=Rise of Her Lady Physician=
=صعود سيدتها الطبيبة=
=Episode 27=
=الحلقة 27=
=Zelan Clears Her Mother's Name=
=زيلان تبرئ اسم والدتها=
Wretch!
البائس!
You're truly a heartless, venomous demon!
أنت حقا شيطان عديم القلب وسام!
You harmed my offspring
لقد أذيت نسلي
and ruined my harem!
ودمرت حريمي!
I'm a demon?
انا شيطان؟
You're the reason
أنت السبب
why I've ended up like this.
لماذا انتهى بي الأمر هكذا.
It's all your fault.
إنه خطؤك كله.
How dare you?
كيف تجرؤ؟
What did I do wrong?
ماذا فعلت خطأ؟
You've been delaying the appointment of the Crown Prince.
لقد أخرتم تعيين ولي العهد؟
You once told me...
لقد قلت لي ذات مرة...
You said my son was the one
لقد قلت أن ابني هو الشخص المناسب
you valued the most!
لقد قدرت أكثر من أي شيء!
You said you'd make him the Crown Prince!
قلت أنك ستجعله ولي العهد!
And then?
وثم؟
You said the same to the others.
قلت نفس الشيء للآخرين.
You treat all of us as pawns,
أنت تعاملنا جميعًا كبيادق،
moving us around at will on the board of power!
تحريكنا كما يحلو لنا على لوحة القوة!
Dad...
أب...
Dad!
أب!
Why would you do this to me?
لماذا تفعل هذا بي؟
I had someone I loved!
لقد كان لدي شخص احبه!
We were deeply in love!
لقد كنا في الحب بعمق!
However, for the sake of the family,
ومع ذلك، من أجل الأسرة،
you forcibly sent me into
لقد أرسلتني بالقوة إلى
the cruel Imperial Palace!
القصر الإمبراطوري القاسي!
You also told me to give birth to a son
لقد طلبت مني أيضًا أن أنجب ابنًا
so that I could make him the Crown Prince
حتى أتمكن من جعله ولي العهد
and bring honor to the whole family!
وجلب الشرف لجميع أفراد الأسرة!
Therefore,
لذلك،
I had no choice but to eliminate anyone in my way.
لم يكن أمامي خيار سوى القضاء على أي شخص في طريقي.
(Behind the vermilion walls)
(خلف الجدران القرمزية)
(are stairs built with bones.)
(هل السلالم مبنية من العظام)
(Beneath the gilded honor)
(تحت الشرف المذهب)
(lies countless tears and blood.)
(يكمن عدد لا يحصى من الدموع والدماء.)
(Those rules praised as feminine virtue)
(تلك القواعد التي أشاد بها البعض باعتبارها فضيلة أنثوية)
(have become blades pressed to our throat.)
(أصبحت شفرات مضغوطة على حناجرنا.)
(Some use them to climb,)
(يستخدمها البعض للتسلق)
(while others are driven to madness.)
(بينما يصل الآخرون إلى الجنون.)
(In the end,)
(في النهاية،)
(We're all pitiable souls trapped in the same invisible cage.)
(نحن جميعا أرواح مثيرة للشفقة محاصرة في نفس القفص غير المرئي.)
Silence!
الصمت!
How dare you distort the truth
كيف تجرؤ على تحريف الحقيقة
and talk nonsense!
وتكلم هراء!
Starting today,
ابتداء من اليوم،
Consort Ning is stripped of her title!
تم تجريد الزوجة نينج من لقبها!
Grant her poisoned wine!
أعطها النبيذ المسموم!
Wait.
انتظر.
The Second Prince didn't die.
الأمير الثاني لم يمت.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
He survived.
لقد نجا.
My son is alive,
ابني على قيد الحياة
right?
يمين؟
My son is still alive, right?
ابني لا يزال على قيد الحياة، أليس كذلك؟
Drag her out!
إسحبها للخارج!
My son is still alive!
ابني لا يزال على قيد الحياة!
Is that true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Rong Zelan.
رونغ زيلان.
Well done again.
أحسنت مرة أخرى.
You didn't let me down.
لم تخذلني.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
شكرا لك جلالتك.
This is my duty as a healer.
هذا واجبي كمعالج.
Lingxiao.
لينجشياو.
Now that the matter is over,
الآن وقد انتهى الأمر،
it's time for you to leave the bureau.
لقد حان الوقت لمغادرة المكتب.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم جلالتك.
Oh, no.
أوه لا.
We mocked His Highness like that.
لقد سخرنا من سموه بهذه الطريقة.
He definitely won't let us off.
إنه بالتأكيد لن يسمح لنا بالخروج.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Who would've thought he's actually
من كان يظن أنه في الواقع
the famous Marquis Xuanping's heir?
وريث الماركيز شوانبينغ الشهير؟
What should we do now?
ماذا يجب علينا أن نفعل الآن؟
Take a look at this.
إلق نظرة على هذا.
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
Previously, I was too ignorant.
في السابق، كنت جاهلاً جداً.
I shouldn't have mocked you for using connections.
لا ينبغي لي أن أسخر منك لاستخدامك الاتصالات.
I deserve punishment!
أنا أستحق العقاب!
Your Highness, please forgive me!
صاحب السمو، من فضلك سامحني!
We were so stupid.
لقد كنا أغبياء جداً.
We shouldn't have said you were hopeless.
لا ينبغي لنا أن نقول أنك يائس.
Please forgive me!
رجائاً أعطني!
He had it coming.
لقد كان يستحق ذلك.
He wouldn't listen to us.
لم يستمع إلينا.
You want me to forgive you.
تريد مني أن أسامحك.
Well, I can forgive you.
حسنًا، أستطيع أن أسامحك.
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
For the whole day today,
طوال اليوم اليوم،
whenever you see someone, you must say,
كلما رأيت شخصًا، يجب أن تقول،
"I am completely
"أنا تماما
hopeless."
"لا أمل."
If you can do this, I'll consider forgiving you.
إذا تمكنت من فعل هذا، فسوف أفكر في مسامحتك.
Yes, Your Highness!
نعم يا صاحب السمو!
Thanks, Your Highness!
شكرا لك، صاحب السمو!
I'm completely
انا تماما
hopeless!
ميؤوس منها!
I'm completely hopeless!
أنا ميؤوس منها تماما!
Well...
حسنًا...
Why are you looking at me like this?
لماذا تنظر إلي بهذه الطريقة؟
Is something wrong?
هل هناك شيء خاطئ؟
Or maybe...
أو ربما...
Are you enchanted by me?
هل أنت مسحور بي؟
You brought me here.
لقد أحضرتني إلى هنا.
Anything to say?
هل لديك أي شيء لتقوله؟
I've completed my mission
لقد أكملت مهمتي
at the Imperial Medical Bureau.
في المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
I can no longer stay
لم يعد بإمكاني البقاء
in the palace every day.
في القصر كل يوم.
Be safe.
كن آمنا.
Be safe?
هل أنت آمن؟
Is that all you want to say?
هل هذا كل ما تريد قوله؟
Yes.
نعم.
It's getting late.
لقد أصبح الوقت متأخرًا.
The gates will be locked soon.
سيتم إغلاق الأبواب قريبا.
Are you leaving today?
هل ستغادر اليوم؟
You…
أنت…
Do you really want me to leave?
هل تريدني حقا أن أرحل؟
Hey!
يا!
Lord Song.
اللورد سونغ.
I will.
أنا سوف.
Do you know what I'm going to say?
هل تعرف ماذا سأقول؟
You will what?
ماذا ستفعل؟
No matter what you say,
بغض النظر عما تقوله،
I will agree.
سأوافق.
I wonder if you have someone you like.
أتساءل عما إذا كان لديك شخص تحبه.
If not,
إذا لم يكن كذلك،
let's get engaged.
دعونا نخطب.
Okay.
تمام.
But...
لكن...
This is a big deal.
هذه صفقة كبيرة.
Shouldn't you
ألا ينبغي لك؟
inform your family first?
أخبر عائلتك أولاً؟
My mother passed away.
لقد توفيت والدتي.
I can decide
انا استطيع ان اقرر
who I will marry.
من سأتزوج؟
Okay.
تمام.
Then we'll do it.
ثم سنفعل ذلك.
Today,
اليوم،
I'd like to share
أريد أن أشارك
a piece of good news with you.
خبر سار معك.
Your Majesty, please be clear.
جلالتك، من فضلك كن واضحا.
Rong Zelan,
رونغ زيلان،
with extraordinary skills,
مع مهارات غير عادية،
has turned the tide many times
لقد قلبت الموازين عدة مرات
and saved many.
وأنقذ كثيرين.
She's not only carried forward ulcer treatment
لم تكتفِ بعلاج القرحة فحسب
among the army
بين الجيش
but also developed special prescriptions,
ولكنهم طوروا أيضًا وصفات خاصة،
benefiting all the people.
مما يعود بالنفع على جميع الناس.
She's professional and compassionate,
إنها محترفة ومتعاطفة،
truly a role model for physicians across the realm.
إنه حقًا نموذج يحتذى به للأطباء في جميع أنحاء المملكة.
I've decided to appoint Rong Zelan
لقد قررت تعيين رونغ زيلان
as the first female imperial physician
كأول طبيبة إمبراطورية
in Great Liang!
في ليانغ العظيمة!
I
أنا
accept the decree!
اقبل المرسوم!
Thanks, Your Majesty!
شكرا جلالتك!
In addition,
فضلاً عن ذلك،
the case of my mother's birthday banquet from ten years ago
حالة حفل عيد ميلاد والدتي منذ عشر سنوات
has been solved.
تم حلها.
Liu Fuling's diagnosis and treatment of my mother
تشخيص وعلاج ليو فولينغ لوالدتي
were timely and appropriate
كانت في الوقت المناسب ومناسبة
without any mistakes.
بدون أي أخطاء.
I've issued a decree
لقد أصدرت مرسوما
to restore her reputation
لاستعادة سمعتها
and set the record straight.
وتوضيح الأمور.
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
I'm grateful for this!
أنا ممتن لهذا!
Song Lingxiao.
سونغ لينغشياو.
You're looking at her so fondly.
أنت تنظر إليها بحنان شديد.
Are you really that impatient?
هل أنت حقا غير صبور إلى هذه الدرجة؟
I've
لقد
long heard of the romance between
لقد سمعنا منذ فترة طويلة عن الرومانسية بين
you and Physician Rong.
أنت والطبيب رونغ.
Today,
اليوم،
I'll do you a favor.
سأقدم لك خدمة.
I'll bestow the marriage
سأمنح الزواج
for you two.
لكما الاثنين.
Wonderful.
رائع.
Great.
عظيم.
Thanks, Your Majesty!
شكرا جلالتك!
(Imperial Decree) By His Majesty's decree,
(المرسوم الإمبراطوري) بموجب مرسوم جلالة الملك،
Rong Zelan, Imperial Physician of the Imperial Medical Bureau,
رونغ زيلان، الطبيب الإمبراطوري في المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري،
with great skills and benevolence,
بمهارات عظيمة وإحسان،
has cured grave illnesses and saved many in the palace.
لقد قام بشفاء أمراض خطيرة وأنقذ العديد من الأشخاص في القصر.
Song Lingxiao, Heir of Marquis Xuanping,
سونغ لينغشياو، وريث الماركيز شوان بينغ
is a loyal and brave man.
هو رجل مخلص وشجاع.
They're both pillars of the nation.
كلاهما من ركائز الأمة.
With deep affection for each other,
مع المودة العميقة لبعضنا البعض،
they truly make a perfect match.
إنهم يشكلون حقا مباراة مثالية.
I hereby bestow the marriage.
أمنح بموجب هذا الزواج.
They may choose an auspicious day for the wedding.
يمكنهم اختيار يوم مناسب للزفاف.
Hope they live in harmony
أتمنى أن يعيشوا في وئام
and build a happy family.
وبناء أسرة سعيدة.
End of the decree!
إنتهى المرسوم!
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
thank you for your grace!
شكرا لنعمتك!